Hi, in this lesson, you will learn how to use quad completions featured from a hard
copilot like a pro.
I will show you different use cases, some related features will give you some tips, recommendations,
and show you keyboard shortcuts you can use.
So to get started, you need to create a new file, I will name it date.js, and it
helps you need to check that code completions are enabled in your settings.
If you hover on copilot icon at the bottom panel, you see it's checked, of this is the
way how you can to go it on or off.
So, and when it's enabled, we can start typing something and see the suggestions.
So, I will implement the date util class, okay, we see suggestions from a copilot, the implementation
of the class is suggest to have the current date method, format date, part date is
what it date, let's imagine it's something we want to implement, and in that case, we can
accept it using the top like this, so it will have the close suggestion, we can accept
it word by word, in case we want to set for example only the first method and the rest
we want to write different way, so I do the exception word by word, and the rest we can
implement different way, so we also can decline the suggestion, let me back changes.
For a moment you can click escape to decline the suggestion, or you can also ignore the
suggestion, you start typing something different like I want to name in date helper and have
the different implementation started with the constructor, so this is the way how we ignore
it, but let's accept all the suggestion, also if you work in file which already contains
some part of the code, compile it you'll try to analyze your coding style and do suggestions
following your coding styles, so to be more relevant for you.
And next feature you can use is alternative suggestions, imagine you want to implement
a new method, and compile it just you wish methods you can implement, so you can we have
option to add this method and this between method, and we can accept the method we like.
Also, there is an option to generate a set generate code from performance, in case you
need to provide some detailed instructions, for compile it to have some quick implementation.
So, let's imagine our implementation and provide a comment that create a date utwise initial
date defined in one structure and methods add, subtract and format, and you see if you follow
our instruction, we have constructor where we define the initial date, we have method
to add this, and to subtract this and to format this, and we can accept it, so the format
and string which is don't really use, so we can delete it, so you see the code, compile
it suggests it's not always perfect, and it's our responsibility to align it to our code
base, to refactor it to apply some changes, okay, so this option you can use when you want
to provide some detailed instruction, what to do, and we can of course remove the comment,
the next feature I want to show you is next edit suggestions, hover and compile it icon
and enable it, if it's not enabled, and what this feature does, this feature analyze all
your code, and if you for example create do some change which might affect the rest of the
code, it will provide the suggestions in these areas of the code, and also make an update,
let me show you, let's imagine we want to have some default date, like date, ring, default,
we save it, for example I want to edit the default value right here in constructor, I click
on a constructor, and you see it do the suggestion to implement it, and it might apply it,
for example it also can be useful when we do some refactoring, when we rename in matters,
like I want to rename it to add this, you see it even suggest us to do it, and it also
kind of lines the rest of the methods to have the same warning, the next option, like it can
be useful during the refactoring, when you want to rename some variables, I want to rename
it to current date, and you see do suggestion for us to rename it also in the rest of the
methods, if you distracted by showing these suggestions you can hold up them, let me show
you how to do it, so you can open settings of these also to your code, find this option,
a detour inline suggest, edit, show collapsed, and just enable it, and now when you, so
let's rename it again, current date, okay, the option is not applied, right, we need to
know close the file and open it again, yeah, how it works, you see it doesn't show the
suggestion, but if we hover on a sidebar, you see it's expand and it's we can apply it,
so we can also apply it for the rest of the file, but I will disable this option because
I like when it shows the changes, how it will look like, for example you also need to implement
it updated right here, it sometimes might be lucky and don't suggest rename it in all
the places where it used, so we just need to help it, for example we click on this date,
like you see something broke, so, okay, what if we do the renaming again, yeah, you see
yeah, now it works fine and suggest to do it in the old code correctly, okay, also next
line suggestions can help us to fix some mistakes, for example if we did the run calculation,
so it just as how it can be fixed, I shall be on it, really simple example, but if you have
more complex logic, the power that can also deal with it, so I call this last one was
useful for you and once more tip might be useful, if you have a large code base and you
want that your suggestions will be based on text of a few files, you might just have
them open close to a file and compile it when do the suggestions, we also analyze this file
and suggestions will be better quality, so I'll see you in the next one, thank you.